Hello everyone, welcome back to our post web SQL tutorial series. So today here we are going to
create for how to insert data into the post-grid SQL table using for the insert into statement.
So first of all, just understand the post-grid SQL insert into. So insert into statement
the post-grid SQL is used to add a new row of data into a table and it allows us to specify the
column and their values for each record that explores how it works with some example. So first of
all here we can insert the data into table, explicit column name. So now just go here and first of all
we'll use the first table, implies table information use. So previously we have created this table
and now we can insert some data code. So first of all we'll just type the insert into the table so
just like the employees and here in this inside first of all type the employee and underscore ID.
So now just check so here simply the ID first name last name and then the employee. So simply create
for the ID and here insert the first name then the last name and also for here the email column
okay. So now here I'm going with the values so and the parenthesis first of all here is the
one and first name for the genie then the last name I have defined for the genie and genismite
okay and here I have prepared for the email call this genie at the right gmail.com okay. So now
here create a single quotation inside because it will not get declared perfectly. So here I have
completely created this statement and here I can simply insert here the new statement we had a new
record for the employee stable and explicitly specify the column name followed by the corresponding
value of its column okay. And now just here I can select all and then execute now you can see here
it is created for the operation is successful okay and the first way of school will return the
confirmation message for the one row is completely affected. So here is completely done and now
just go for the another example we create and here insert the data into the table for the default
keyword okay. So now here is in another table information so first of all here I'll just type this
the insert into for the table name suppose like the receiving product. So in this insert first of all
I will create for the product unless for the ID also the product unless for the main column
and also here here this is the price okay. So now just check so again here it is the product ID
name and the price okay. So this is perfect and here I can just go into a next step and here I can
see it for the some values and just like the values first I'll create the product ID is
one okay and then it was for the product name for the interface so develop the ID and next step
here I'll put this is a. So you can see here product understand and now here simply create
certain product report into the product table and provide the value for the product name
column and use the default keyword for the price column okay and along with the use the
default value as defined for the table is key okay and now just here select all and then execute
now so just to it and you can see here this is the one row completely affected okay.
So now just take and verify so first of all open another new query and here type for this
to select 12 from the table name this called the product okay. So now just simply select an execute
and you can see here this is the quickly now okay. So I hope you understand and next step here
multiple column to use so just go for here and then use for another so now just define for
the 2 and then here create the name change for suppose like the Sarah and here I can use change
this the Sarah okay so right here the Sarah okay and also here I can create for another column
so now just copy okay and paste for here this the next line the semicolon I'm now just change
for the most change for template 83 and here I can create the name of johan then
there the smith smi th okay joan smith and here I can change for demo address so now just
define for this is the okay so now here for 50 quid for the multiple inside data query and first of all
I'll select all and then execute and you can see here the the 2 row is completely affected so
I can just open for the employee stable all the records so here I can create start select multiple
signs for the prompt and here I can type this is the employees okay. So now just select all
and then execute and you can see here perfectly see the results of first of all create
ID and the first name last name and also for the email addresses okay so here are the three
different rows in the employee table and here in the session completely done and perfectly
inserting data query into the post grade SQL table okay for some practical example okay so
I hope you perfectly understand the session so thank you for watching and happy coding okay